VAISHNO KUMAR

Portfolio: https://vaishnokmr.github.io/my-portfolio.github.io/ Email: kumarvaishnav17@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/Vaishnokmr

Mobile: +918126159737LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vaishno-kumar/ Location: Mirzapur (UP)

Medium: https://medium.com/@kumarvaishnav17

Summary

Data Scientist with strong math background and 2+ years of experience using predictive modeling, data processing, and data mining algorithms to solve challenging business problems. My research interests lie in Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, and Recommendation Systems.

EDUCATION

Uttarakhand Technical University, Roorkee College of Engineering

Bachelor of Technology - Electrical and Electronics Engineering

Roorkee, Uttarakhand August 2013 - June 2017

EXPERIENCE

• Axes Geeks Pvt Ltd , Noida, UP | Machine Learning Engineer

July 2022 - January 2023

- o Utilized python to implement OpenCV and tesseract for extract information (eg: ID, Name, Address, etc) from 250 or above page pdf and export into excel with approx 95%- 97% accuracy, which reduced total process time by 20%.
- Wrangled trading data stored in parquet file to RFM model (recency, frequency, and monetary) and visualize to understand the company's market behavior and decision-making to revive the market.
- o Presented results to team's global head and wrote requested executive summary detailing value proposition and strategy to present to end clients and senior leadership.
- o Displayed a working knowledge of data visualization and statistical method in python to develop visualizations and implement analyzes
- Ineuron.ai, Bangalore, KA | Data Scientist Intern

September 2021 - March 2022

- o Data wrangling/munging/slicing, cleaning and translation, dealing with missing data, data pre-processing/cleaning treated outliers to deliver impact analysis.
- Implement ML algorithms technique for creating the best working models and bring up from 63% to 92% prediction
- o Make a web app with the help of Django and deployed it on the cloud platform to make user friendly to check rating prediction.
- The Sparks Foundation, | Data Scientist Intern

June 2021 - August 2021

- o Creating Algorithms based on deep-dive Statistical Analysis predictive data modelling. Deploying quantitate analysis and data visualization to present data.
- o Hands-on experience with various tools, technologies, and methods to achieve the predicted output.
- o Design, run and measure experiments to test business hypotheses. Insight generation against a recurring use case
- Videotex Int Pvt Ltd , Greater Noida, UP | MIS Analyst (CONTRACT)

- Reduce takt time 10% based on analyzed monthly data and increase production growth by 15% 20% and maintained on-time shipment record of 95% and above
- Sustained 60% production growth with 20% increase in production staff based on KPIs
- Make quarterly and half yearly performance details & Performance status report with the help of ERP.

SKILLS SUMMARY

• Python, MySQL, Machine Learning, NLP (Natural Language Processing), Recommendation Engines, Customer Segmentation & Retation Models, A/B testing, Statistics, Tableau, Excel, Git, Problem-Solving

Projects

Cab Demand-Supply Forecasting: To find a number of pickups, given location coordinates (latitude and longitude) and time, in the query region and surrounding regions.

Tech Stack: Python, Time-Series Forecasting, Cluster and Segmentations, Predictive Modeling, and Analysis, Scikit-learn Project Details: Click here

• Restaurant rating prediction: The main goal of this project is to perform extensive Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) on the Zomato Dataset and build an appropriate Machine Learning Model that will help various Zomato Restaurants to predict their respective Ratings based on certain features.

Tech Stack: Python, Machine learning, Predictive modeling and Analysis, Scikit-learn, Django Project Details: Click here

• Retails Sales Analytics & Insights: The main goal of this project is to perform extensive Analytics & Insights on Retails Store Dataset. The data contains hundreds of thousands of electronics store purchases broken down by month, product type, cost, purchase address, etc.

Tech Stack: Python, Data modeling, Analysis Insights, ETL, Tableau, Dashboard Reports.

Project Details: Click here